あ、あの真面目な息子があんな雑誌を…
I can't believe that my son, who's so serious, would go and look at those sorts of magazines...
Onii-chan, it's dinner time!
お兄ちゃん～、ご～はん～だよ
Using my right hand to continue solving problems, I can use my left hand to write down names... and to take out potato chips to eat.
右手で方程式を解き続け…
左手で名前を書き
Using my right hand to continue solving problems, I can use my left hand to write down names... and to take out potato chips to eat.
ポテチを取り…食べる！
L himself will be the witness to my alibi.
僕のアリバイの目撃者は L 本人だ
Contact
Are you certain, Ryuk?
絶対だな、リューク
Yeah, I'm sure there's no one following you.
ああ、絶対に尾行はついてない
は…早くしてくれ、禁断症状が…
H-Hurry!! The withdrawal symptoms... they're--
You aren't just making this up so that you can eat your apples, are you?
リンゴ食べたくて、適当なことを言ってるんじゃないだろうな
Hey! I've already circled multiple times, within a 100m radius around you to check.
おいおい、オレはライトの半径百メートル以内を
何度も飛び回って確認したんだ
Hey! I've already circled multiple times, within a 100m radius around you to check.
I'm sure.
絶対だよ
Okay, but they did mention on the news that there are supposed to be 1,500 more investigators.
しかし、ニュースで1500人の捜査員の導入というのもあったしな
脅しに決まってるだろう
They're just trying to intimidate you, and you know it.
You said it yourself; it it was true, they would never have made such a big fuss about it.
お前だって、
「本当ならこっそり入れるはず」と言ってたじゃないか
わかったよ、リューク
Fine, Ryuk.
I'll buy you an apple.
リンゴ、買ってやるよ
Success!!
やったぁ
Here, thanks a lot.
はい、毎度あり
ライト、はやく、はやく
Light! Faster, faster!
しかし、死神使い荒いじゃん
You know, you don't treat Shinigami very well, do ya?
I can't believe that you made me give up eating apples in the house till I'd managed to find all those cameras.
カメラを探し出させておいて、
家の中でリンゴ食うのは諦めろだもんなぁ
Come on now, eat the core as well.
ちゃんと芯まで食べろよ
お前、本当に仕舞いにはオレのデスノートに名前を書いて殺すぞ
You know that I'm definitely going to write your name in my Death Note in the end, right?
はは…
Is this really the time to be laughing?
笑ってる場合かよ
You're right. I still have things I need to finish.
そうだな、まだ最後の仕上げが残っている
Ryuuzaki.
竜崎…
Yes?
はい
Two days ago, a mugger and an embezzler died of heart attacks, despite the fact that my family had no knowledge of them.
一昨日の引ったくり犯と横領犯の心臓麻痺、
あれは私の家族が情報得てない間に起きた
Two days ago, a mugger and an embezzler died of heart attacks, despite the fact that my family had no knowledge of them.
疑いが晴れたのでは？
Do you still suspect them?
Let me see...
そうですね、いくらキラが死の時間を操れても、
Even if Kira can manipulate the time of death, they wouldn't be able to kill someone without seeing those broadca---
報道を見る前に死の時間を持ってこられるとは考えられま…
Your son is home again.
また息子さんが帰ってきました
ちぇ、まただんまりで勉強の振りか
You're going to stay silent and pretend to study again?
I've already memorized the locations of all the cameras.
もうカメラの位置は全て把握してある
However, the only criminals I was able to kill using the potato chips' packet as a cover were a mugger and an embezzler.
だが、ポテチの仕掛けで殺せたのは、引ったくり犯と横領犯
Both are quite notably less serious crimes than the usual.
今までに比べれは罪の軽い者になってしまった…
では、続いてのニュースです
And next on the news...
Are you going to watch TV?
なぁ、テレビ見るの？
... are still under investigation.
Even if there are criminals dying while I'm not watching TV or using the Internet,
僕がテレビやネット見ていない時に、
報道された犯罪者が死んでも、
逆に僕が報道得ていない時にだけ、
軽い罪の者が死んだということで、
it'll still look suspicious that the lesser criminals only die when I don't appear to be getting any information.
疑うことも可能ではある
Therefore, if I kill some of the lesser criminals while they can see me watching the TV, they'll have no reason to treat those deaths as unusual.
つまり、僕がテレビを見ている時に報道された
罪の軽い犯罪者も殺しておけば、特別視されない
Therefore, if I kill some of the lesser criminals while they can see me watching the TV, they'll have no reason to treat those deaths as unusual.
Also, regardless of the seriousness of their crimes, I can remember the names and faces of the criminals for when I get out of the house.
そして、外に出た時の為に、
罪の重さに関わらず、
ニュース等で報道された者の名前を憶えておき、
Also, regardless of the seriousness of their crimes, I can remember the names and faces of the criminals for when I get out of the house.
Then, using the piece of Death Note I keep in my wallet, I can scatter their times of death as I please.
財布の中に仕込んでおいたデスノートで…
死の時間を適当にばらつかせ、殺す…
My anti-surveillance camera plan is finally complete.
これで監視カメラ対策は完璧だ
I've been over the audio and the video footage from the last five days a countless number of times.
この数日間の盗聴テープと
カメラ影像のビデオを何度も再生し、検証してみました
結論から言わせてもらいます
I'd like to share my conclusions with you all.
Within the Kitamura and Yagami households, I observed suspicious behaviour from... no one.
北村家、夜神家の中で怪しい者は…
いません
Within the Kitamura and Yagami households, I observed suspicious behaviour from... no one.
I'll remove all the surveillance cameras and bugging devices.
カメラと盗聴器をはずします
はぁ…
So there weren't any suspects after all...
結局、容疑者は居ず、かぁ…
Hang in there!
気をぬくな、もう一度引き締め直すんだ
We need to pull ourselves together and start over.
Please, don't get the wrong idea.
勘違いしないで下さい
What I actually mean is that, judging by this footage alone, there doesn't appear to be anyone that's suspicious.
「影像を見ている限りは、怪しい者はいない」という意味です
What?!
え…？
Even if Kira were amongst them, they've done nothing to expose themselves.
あの中にキラはいたとしても､ボロは出しません
If anything, they appear to be killing criminals as usual.
いや、
何も出さずに今まで通り犯罪者を葬っているということです
If anything, they appear to be killing criminals as usual.
So, Ryuuzaki, do you think that Kira may still be one of them?
では、竜崎はやはりキラは、あの中にいると…
ですから…五パーセントです
As I've said before... there's a 5% chance.
Even though the cameras were up, Kira continued to kill.
監視カメラがついている間にも、キラによる殺人は行われていた
どんな方法で殺人を行っているか分らないが、
I don't know how they're killing people... even if they could kill someone by just by wishing for it to happen...
仮に念じるだけで人を殺せるとしても…
Each time that happened, a normal person should react in some way... they would reveal it by their expression, or through their behavior.
普通の人間であれば殺しを行うさえ、
挙動や表情に何らかの変化はあっていいはず…
Each time that happened, a normal person should react in some way... they would reveal it by their expression, or through their behavior.
あの中にキラはいない…そう考えるのが普通だろう
"Kira isn't among them".. that would be the "normal" conclusion one would draw.
しかし、もしキラがあの中にいるのなら…
Yet, if Kira is among them, within their own mind, they're already a god.
キラの精神は既に神の域に達している
They'll kill without blinking an eye.
顔色ひとつ変えず悪人を裁いている…
もはやキラなど存在しない、
It's as though there is no Kira, but that this is really the work of God.
本当に神の裁きと考えたいほどだ…
But there's no way that God requires a name and a face in order to kill!
しかし、神が人を殺すのに、
顔と名前が必要なんてふざけている…
This isn't the work of God.
これは、神の裁きではなく、
神の裁きを気取った子供じみた者がいる
It's just some kid who likes to think that they are God.
That's what it is.
そういうことだ
Somewhere, out there, a serial killer called "Kira" exists, and I will catch them!
キラという大量殺人犯は必ず存在する…そして必ず捕まえる
Even if the cameras were to be maintained, I doubt that Kira would exhibit any signs by their behavior.
しかし、このままカメラをつけ続けていても、
キラが殺しの兆候や態度を見せるとは思えない
What should I do?
どうすればいい…
It seems like the best method would be to make them admit that they are Kira and demonstrate how they kill people.
自分がキラですと言ってもらい
殺しを実際にやってみせてもらうが一番いい…
But surely, that's going to be impossible...
そんなことできるはずが…
Hey, Light. As I thought, the cameras are gone.
おいライト、やっぱりカメラ取れてるぞ
All of them. The lot!
全部だ、全部
ライト、聞いてるのか
Light? You listening?
なぁライト
Hey, Light!
Oh, I've got ya; there may still be bugging devices.
お、そうか、まだ盗聴器はついているかもしれないのか
I guess this means that I'm no longer a target of their investigations, although, L will doubtlessly continue to pursue Kira.
これで僕は捜査対象から外れた…
計算通りだ
I guess this means that I'm no longer a target of their investigations, although, L will doubtlessly continue to pursue Kira.
しかし L はキラを追い続けるだろう、
However, as long as he continues to use the Japanese police force, my father will be in the middle of that investigation.
だが、まだ日本警察を使っているのなら…
その動かしている者の中に、必ず父はいる
In that case... I can use my father to reveal L's real identity.
だとすれば…父を利用して L の正体を掴み、消すこと…
L さえ消せば
If I can erase L... Kira will be one step closer to becoming the God of a new world.
キラは新世界の神にまた一歩近づく…
Light, hurry up!
ライト、早くしなさい
Go for it.
しっかりね
Onii-chan, do your best!
お兄ちゃん、がんばって！
Really, stop making such a fuss.
まったく大袈裟だな、行ってきます
I'm off then.
It's a relief to know that the bugging devices have also been removed.
しかし、盗聴器もない事が判ってすっきりしたな
It's good that that's one less thing I need to stress about before my exams.
まぁ、試験前に一つのストレス要因は無くなってよかった
Toudou University
Heisei 19 (2007) University Entrance Exams
Plus, getting into university will allow me more time to act as "Kira", and the time to go after L.
そして大学に入ってしまえば
キラとして動く時間… L を探る時間もとり易くなる…
Plus, getting into university will allow me more time to act as "Kira", and the time to go after L.
You there! There's only ten minutes left before the exams starts!
君、試験開始十分前だよ、早くしなさい
Hurry up!
I hate having to wait around in classrooms, so I was planning to be here three minutes before it starts, but oh well... I managed to arrive earlier than I intended.
教室で待つの嫌だから、三分前に入ろうと思ってたのに…
早く着いたな
Wow, he doesn't lack confidence.
すげぇ余裕
始め！
Begin!
You there! Number 162. Sit down properly!
そこ、受験番号百六十二番
ちゃんと座りなさい
Lately, there's been a load of guys watching the Human World for all they're worth...
最近、やけに一生懸命人間界見てる奴多いけど、
なんだあれ
What's going on?
Apparently, Ryuk is being kept as a pet by a human.
リュークが人間に飼われているらしい
W-What the hell is he thinking?!
な、何考えてんだい､一体
God damn it! He's got no pride as a Shinigami!
まったく、死神のプライド丸潰れだ
No, I was talking about the human.
いや、オレの言っているのは飼ってる人間のほう
あ？
Ryuk would make a terrible pet. He's not cute at all.
リューク、ペットにしたって可愛くも何ともないだろう
Too right!
そりゃそうだ
What's his owner like? Female? Male?
で、飼ってる人間ってどんな奴？女、男？
No idea.
さぁ
オレはちょっと覗いてこよっと…
Might go and take a look myself.
Oh boy, oh boy...
やれやれ…
Heisei 19 (2007) Toudou University Entrance Ceremony
ライトも大学生か
So, Light, you're now a university student. I'm somewhat overwhelmed.
なんかこう、感無量だな
The Freshman's speech.
新入生挨拶
Introducing the freshmen's representative, Yagami Light...
新入生代表、夜神月
Here.
はい
Wow, amazing.
お、すげぇ
and also... Ryuuga Hideki.
同じく新入生代表、流河旱樹
Oh? Here.
あ、はい
流河旱樹って、あのアイドルの？
R-Ryuuga Hideki... do they mean the idol?
Don't be stupid. How is he going to get the grades to get into Toudai?
まさか、あいつに東大入る学力があるかよ
You're right. He doesn't look anything like the idol Ryuuga.
ほんと、アイドルの流河とは、似ても似つかないや
二人で挨拶するとは聞いていたが、
I'd heard that there would be two of us doing this speech... but I can't believe it's with him of all people.
こいつだったとは…
He was behind me during the exams.
センター試験前期日程、ずっと僕の後ろで変な座り方をして
He was sitting in that really odd way that made him stand out...
完全に一人で浮いていた奴だ
New life begins to blossom in the breath of spring...
新たな命が萌えいずる、春の息吹の中…
Doesn't the student with the highest grade in the entrance exam usually give this speech?
これって…入試トップの成績で入った奴がやるんだよな
Finally we're able to embrace this bright future...
That just means that there were two of them this year.
今年はトップが二人だってことだろ？
Today we look forward to...
二人とも全教科満点っていう噂だよ
I heard that both of them got top marks for everything!
Seriously?!
マジで？
People like that really exist, huh?
やっぱいるんだそういうのって
...at Toudou University fairness in society will...
I prefer the one on the right.
あたしは断然右かな…
What?! Kyouko, you're weird... I tell you, normal people would say the one on the left...
え？京子あんた変、普通左だって…
Just look at them though.. They're complete opposites!
しかしあの二人、対照的だな
Yeah.
ああ、
Certainly one looks like a brilliant genius, brought up in a sheltered environment, but... the other one...
一人はいかにも、温室育ちの秀才って感じたが、
もう片方が…
新たな命が萌えいずる春の息吹の中…
New life begins to blossom in the breath of spring...
You could almost call him feral...
野性的というか、相当変わってるな…
ああいうのは天才肌って言うのか
Isn't he what one would describe as a natural genius?
Wearing that sort of garb to the entrance ceremony at Toudai, he's either an idiot, or he's mocking the ceremony.
東大の入学式にあの服装、で、挨拶、
なめてるか馬鹿か、どっちかだ
...freshmen's representative, Ryuuga Hideki.
新入生代表、流河旱樹
夜神君、
Yagami-kun.
The son of police chief, Yagami Souichirou. You have a sense of justice that matches your father's.
警察庁、夜神総一郎局長の息子さんであり、
その父に負けないくらいの正義感の持ち主
なんだ、こいつ…
What's with this guy?
You're aiming for a career in the Police Force yourself, and in the past you've helped in several cases that have all led to convictions.
そして自らも警察官僚を目指し、
過去に数件の事件へ助言し解決に導き
You're aiming for a career in the Police Force yourself, and in the past you've helped in several cases that have all led to convictions.
And right now, you're interested in the Kira case.
今、キラ事件にも興味を示している
With that sense of justice and ability, I could trust you with a very important secret, if you promise not to tell anyone.
その正義感と手腕を信じて、
もし誰にも漏らさないと誓って頂ければ、
With that sense of justice and ability, I could trust you with a very important secret, if you promise not to tell anyone.
はなし
キラ事件に関する重大な事を話したいと思っています
I'd like to tell you something very important regarding the Kira case.
What's with this? All of a sudden...
なんなんだ突然…
こいつ、相手にしないほうがいいのか…
It might be wiser if I don't talk to him.
Then again, what's this "important thing" concerning the Kira case?
しかし、キラ事件に関する重大な事って…
I won't tell anyone. What is it?
誰にも言わないよ、何？
I'm L.
私は L です…
ま…まさか
N-No way.
何を言ってるんだこいつ
What the hell is he saying?!
L が L だと言うはずがない
There's no way L would admit to being L.
I thought he seemed a little odd, but is he actually crazy?
変な奴だとは思っていたが、マジでおかしいのか…
W-Wait. I can't show that I'm uneasy. If he really is L...
ま…まずい、
動揺するな、もし本当に L だったら、
W-Wait. I can't show that I'm uneasy. If he really is L...
In any case, right now, I've got to act as people would expect Yagami Souichirou's son, Yagami Light, to act...
とにかくここは、夜神総一郎の息子、夜神月として、
自然な行動を取らなくては…
If you really are L, then you are someone I admire a lot.
もしあなたがそうなら、僕の尊敬する、憧れの人です
どうも、名乗ったのはキラ事件解決の力になって
頂けるかもしれないと思ったからです
Thanks.
I revealed myself to you because I believe that you might be able to help us with the Kira case.
Yagami Light. There's only a 5% chance that you are Kira.
夜神月、キラである可能性は五パーセント未満
But out of all those I watched, there's something about you... you're too perfect.
しかしあの中では一番何かを感じさせた…
お前は完璧すぎる。そしてもしお前がキラであれば、
But out of all those I watched, there's something about you... you're too perfect.
If you truly are Kira, this is the best way I can think of to put pressure on you.
これ以上のプレッシャーはないだろ
ふふ、こいつがもし L だとしたら、大したもんだな…
If he's L... That's impressive!
確かに。こいつが L だとしたら…
It's true. If this guy really is L... No, even if he isn't, I... I won't be able to do anything to him!
いや、実は L じゃなくともだ
僕は…
It's true. If this guy really is L... No, even if he isn't, I... I won't be able to do anything to him!
僕は…こいつに何もできない
If he's L, then my father would know his face.
こいつの話が本当なら、父にも L として顔を明かしているだろう
僕に対し、自分が L だと言ったこいつが死んだら、
If he dies after telling me that he's L, I'll immediately become the suspect.
真っ先に僕に疑いがかかる
Plus, this guy is using the blatantly fake name "Ryuuga Hideki".
しかも、こいつ、流河旱樹などと、
あからさまな偽名を使っている
If I try to kill him by writing that name in the Death Note, then if his real name isn't Ryuuga Hideki...
こいつを殺そうとデスノートに名前を書き、
こいつの本名が流河旱樹でなければ…
Ryuuga Hideki
嫌でも頭の中に浮かぶアイドルのほうの流河が…
The idol Ryuuga may die instead, as his face instinctively appears in my mind when I think of that name.
死ぬかもしれない
こいつは死なずに僕がキラだと言う推測が立つ
Without dying himself, he'll be able to tell whether I'm Kira or not.
こいつ… L なのか、そして僕をキラだと疑っているのか、
Is he L? And does he suspect that I'm Kira?
I can't tell to what extent he suspects me, but I'm sure he does.
どの程度か分らないが、疑われているのは確かだ、
There's no other reason to reveal himself to the son of Yagami Souichirou.
他に夜神総一郎の息子に L だと名乗る理由はない
Does this indicate that he's still investigating those who were previously being investigated by Ray Penber?
レイ．ペンバーの調べていた者の範囲で、
まだ捜査しているということか…
しかし、何故 L が直接僕の前に…
But, why is L here, in person?
今はダメだ、
I shouldn't be thinking about this right now. I've got to exhibit a cool demeanor.
何も考えない方がいい
澄ました顔をしていなくては…
I shouldn't be thinking about this right now. I've got to exhibit a cool demeanor.
こいつは絶対、今僕が動揺していないか観察している
He's definitely watching me for a reaction.
ぬふ、面白い入学式だったぜ、ライト
That entrance ceremony was fun, Light!
夜神君
Yagami-kun.
Hey, Light. That guy's calling ya.
おいライト、あいつが呼んでるぜ
Thanks for today.
今日はどうも
いえ、こちらこそ
No, thank you.
Wow, what a car!
すげぇ車…
リムジン？
A limousine?
Well, I'll see you on campus.
じゃあ、今度はキャンパスで
あ…そうだね
Yeah.
どこのぼんぼんだ、あいつ…
His family is probably loaded.
And a top student as well. That's kind of creepy...
しかも首席、やな感じ
Welcome home, Toudai student!
東大生お帰り
Shit!! He got me!
くそっ！やられた！
やられた？
He got you?
Damn it, L! I've never been so humiliated in my life!
L め…こんな屈辱が生まれた初めてだ！
Err.. Hey, you could always just do the trade for the eyes of a Shinigami and kill him...
なぁ…死神の目の取引をして、殺せばいいじゃないか
What if this whole thing turns out to be a trap?!
そんなことをして、もしこれが罠だったらどうする
If I kill him, and it turns out that he isn't L, it'll be as good as telling the real L that I am Kira!
アイツが本当の L じゃなかったら、
L に僕がキラだというようなものなんだよ！
S-Sorry...
お…わ、悪い
A Shinigami killing a human isn't the same as a human killing a human!
死神が人間を殺すのと…
人間が人間を殺すのを同じ次元で考えるな
I want to kill him, no matter what.
なんとしても、アイツを殺してやりたいが…
But if I kill him, they'll trace it back to me.
殺せば足がつく…
デスノートでは、名前を書いたその人間ひとりしか殺せない、
The Death Note can only kill the person whose name is written down, I can't manipulate others into killing him.
誰かを操って殺させることができない…
The Death note is so inconvenient!
まったく不便だよ、デスノートって奴は
いつも冷静なライトが逆切れか、相当きてるな
He's always so calm, but he finally flipped.
At first I thought that I'd only need his name and then I'd be able to kill him via an accident or suicide.
最初は名前さえ分れば、事故死や自殺でいいと考えた…
But, unless I'm 100% sure that he's the real L, it's no use.
しかし、
それはアイツが百パーセント L 本人だと分らなければダメだ…
But, unless I'm 100% sure that he's the real L, it's no use.
No, even if he is the real L, the fact that he's already told me might mean that it's already too late.
いや、 L 本人だと分っても、
僕に L だと宣言した以上、手遅れかもしれない
No, even if he is the real L, the fact that he's already told me might mean that it's already too late.
No matter how he dies, the police will be suspicious.
どんな死に方でも、 L が死ねば警察は疑う…
I underestimated him!
L をなめていた…
L が僕に、
私は L だと名乗り出てくるなんて事は、考えもしなかった…
I'd never have thought that he would reveal himself to me.
Those individuals who he suspects of being Kira... he doesn't have to worry about them, even if he's a substitute for L... he only needs to introduce himself to them as L...
キラの可能性のある者には、 L の分身でも構わない、
L だと名乗っておく
For L, this is an extremely effective defence against Kira... and it's also a form of attack.
これは、 L にとって、
キラに対するかなり有効な防御であると共に、攻撃でもある
For L, this is an extremely effective defence against Kira... and it's also a form of attack.
You got me. It was an excellent move.
やられたよ、いい手だ
Ryuuga might have pretended that he had no ulterior motives, but he'll try and get close to me through university and try to manipulate me.
あの惚けた振りした流河が、
これから大学でどんどん僕に接近し、
Ryuuga might have pretended that he had no ulterior motives, but he'll try and get close to me through university, and try to manipulate me.
操ろうとしてくるだろう
これはいい…何も悲観することはない
This is good.
This is nothing to get depressed about.
This just proves that L has nothing to go on.
これは向こうも何も掴んでいない証拠だ…
あいつも僕もじかに接しての騙し合い…
This is now a straight-forward competition of bluffing and knowledge.
On the surface, it looks like we're "best friends", but in reality, we're both trying to find out whether the other is "L" or "Kira".
知恵比べだ
表面上は仲良しのキャンパスメイト、
裏では L なのか、キラなのかの探りあい…
面白いよ流河、
Interesting. I would never have imagined that you would come, offering me friendship, Ryuuga.
お前が僕に友情を求めてくるなら、快く受け入れてやろう
I'll wholeheartedly accept your friendship, make you believe me, make you divulge all your information, and then kill you... Without fail.
僕はお前を信じ込ませ、そして全てを引き出し…
お前を殺す
この手で必ず…
To be continued
流河旱樹、 L
アイツのこのテニスでプロファイルなんてする筈がない
このテニスの目的は他にある
だからテニスでも、僕が勝つ！